# Global settings for the linux-lab Helm chart
name: file-management-lab
namespace: labs

# Autoscaling settings
autoscaling:
  enabled: false

# Deployment settings
replicaCount: 1

appLabels:
  app: "devopclinics-lab"
  instance: "file-management"


# Image settings
image:
  repository: dclinics/linux-labs
  tag: "v7"
  pullPolicy: IfNotPresent

# Service settings
service:
  name: file-lab-service
  type: NodePort
  port: 5000           # The port on which your app listens
  targetPort: 5000     # The port in the container
  nodePort: 30003  

# Annotations and labels for the pods
podAnnotations: {}
podLabels: {}

# Image pull secrets
imagePullSecrets: []

# Security context for the pod and container
podSecurityContext: {}
securityContext: {}

# Probes for liveness and readiness
livenessProbe:
  httpGet:
    path: /
    port: 5000
  initialDelaySeconds: 5
  timeoutSeconds: 5
readinessProbe:
  httpGet:
    path: /
    port: 5000
  initialDelaySeconds: 5
  timeoutSeconds: 5

# Resource requests and limits
resources: {}

# Volume mounts and volumes
volumeMounts:
  - name: questions-volume
    mountPath: /app/config

volumes:
  - name: questions-volume
    configMap:
      name: file-management-questions

# Node selector, affinity, and tolerations
nodeSelector: {}
affinity: {}
tolerations: {}

selector:
  app.kubernetes.io/name: devopclinics-lab
  app.kubernetes.io/instance: file-management

# Ingress settings
ingress:
  enabled: false
  hosts: []
  tls: false


# ConfigMap data specific to the service
configData:
  configMapName: "linux-file-management-devopclinics-lab-questions"
  config:
    title: "Linux File management lab"
  questions: 
    - question: "Create an empty file named 'example.txt' in the current directory."
      answer: "touch example.txt"
    - question: "Create a directory named 'project' in your home directory."
      answer: "mkdir ~/project"
    - question: "Copy the file 'example.txt' to the 'project' directory."
      answer: "cp example.txt ~/project/"
    - question: "Move the file 'example.txt' from the current directory to the 'project' directory."
      answer: "mv example.txt ~/project/"
    - question: "Rename the file 'example.txt' in the 'project' directory to 'example-renamed.txt'."
      answer: "mv ~/project/example.txt ~/project/example-renamed.txt"
    - question: "Remove the file 'example-renamed.txt' from the 'project' directory."
      answer: "rm ~/project/example-renamed.txt"
    - question: "Delete the directory 'project' and all its contents."
      answer: "rm -r ~/project"
    - question: "List all files and directories in the current directory, including hidden ones."
      answer: "ls -a"
    - question: "Display detailed information about the files in the current directory."
      answer: "ls -l"
    - question: "Show the first 10 lines of the file 'document.txt'."
      answer: "head document.txt"
    - question: "Show the last 10 lines of the file 'document.txt'."
      answer: "tail document.txt"
    - question: "Create a symbolic link named 'shortcut' that points to 'document.txt'."
      answer: "ln -s document.txt shortcut"
    - question: "Change the permissions of 'document.txt' to read and write for the owner, and read-only for the group and others."
      answer: "chmod 644 document.txt"
    - question: "Change the owner of 'document.txt' to the user 'admin'."
      answer: "sudo chown admin document.txt"
    - question: "Change the group ownership of 'document.txt' to the group 'staff'."
      answer: "sudo chown :staff document.txt"
    - question: "Find all files named 'notes.txt' in the current directory and its subdirectories."
      answer: "find . -name 'notes.txt'"
    - question: "Display the contents of 'document.txt' page by page."
      answer: "less document.txt"
    - question: "Count the number of lines, words, and characters in 'document.txt'."
      answer: "wc document.txt"
    - question: "Compress the file 'largefile.txt' using gzip."
      answer: "gzip largefile.txt"
    - question: "Extract the contents of 'largefile.txt.gz'."
      answer: "gunzip largefile.txt.gz"
    - question: "Archive the directory 'project' into a file named 'project.tar'."
      answer: "tar -cvf project.tar project"
    - question: "Extract the contents of 'project.tar' into the current directory."
      answer: "tar -xvf project.tar"
    - question: "Search for the word 'error' in 'logfile.txt' and display matching lines."
      answer: "grep 'error' logfile.txt"
    - question: "Display the size of the file 'document.txt' in human-readable format."
      answer: "du -h document.txt"
    - question: "Create a hard link named 'hardlink' to the file 'document.txt'."
      answer: "ln document.txt hardlink"
